No, seriously, I think I've finally figured out my problem with women.
Sérieux, je pense que j'ai résolu mon problème avec les femmes.
The capybara is the largest member of the rodent family.
Le capybara est le plus gros membre dela famille des rongeurs.
What does that have to do with me and women?
Quel rapport avec moi et les femmes ?
Nothing, it was a desperate attempt...
Aucun. C‘est une tentative désespérée
...to introduce an alternate topic of conversation.
d'introduire un autre sujet de conversation.
My problem is I don't project confidence.
En fait, je ne respire pas la confiance.
So I decided that the next time I meet a woman I think is attractive...
Alors la prochaine fois que je rencontre une femme attirante,
...rather than holding back and being cautious...
plutôt que de me retenir et de prendre des gants,
...l'll assume the mantle of self-assurance.
je me draperai d'une aura d'assurance.
Oh, yeah? What does that look like?
Ah, oui ? Et ça ressemble à quoi ?
Hi.
Bonjour.
I'm Leonard.
Je m‘appelle Leonard.
You are beautiful.
Vous êtes magnifique.
You pop, sparkle and buzz electric.
Vous êtes éclatante, rayonnante, sémillante.
I'm gonna pick you up at 8, show you a night you will never forget.
Je passe vous prendre à 20 h. Ce sera une nuit inoubliable.
Where are we going?
On va où ?
Good news, I made it onto the team for the new Defense Department...
Bonne nouvelle. Je rejoins l'équipe du satellite de surveillance
-...laser-equipped surveillance satellite. -Excuse me.
- du ministère dela Défense. - Pardon.
If we're changing topics, I believe I have first dibs with capybara...
Si on change de sujet, je crois avoir des choses sur le capybara,
...a rodent the size of a baby hippo.
un rongeur de la taille d'un bébé hippopotame.
-Congratulations, Howard. HOWARD: Thanks.
- Félicitations, Howard. - Merci.
Listen, I have to get a security clearance...
Je dois obtenir le certificat de sécurité,
...so you guys might be hearing from the FBI.
alors il se peut que le FBI vous contacte.
Whoa, whoa, Whoa. I don't want to speak to the FBI.
Je ne veux pas parler au FBI.
-Why not? -l'm brown and I talk funny.
- Pourquoi ? - Je suis basané etj'ai un accent.
They're just doing a background check on me.
C‘est mon histoire qu'ils vont Vérifier.
It doesn't matter, they'll find a reason to give me a one-way ticket to Gandhiville.
Et alors ? Ils trouveront une raison pour me renvoyer à Gandhiville.
By the way, when I say that, it's not offensive.
En passant, ce n‘est pas une insulte.
Don't be ridiculous, Raj.
Ne sois pas ridicule, Raj.
-You're here legally. -Nobody cares.
- Tu as tes papiers. - Ça ne change rien.
You know how long it's been since I got through airport security...
Sais-tu depuis quand la sécurité à l'aéroport ne m'impose pas
...without being given a colonoscopy?
une colonoscopie ?
You know, I try very hard to make our lunch hours educational and informative.
J'essaie très fort de rendre ces repas éducatifs et instructifs.
But your insistence on talking about your own lives stymies me at every turn.
Mais vous insiste: pour parler de vos vies et ça me coince.
Fine, Sheldon, tell us about your giant rodents.
Trés bien, Sheldon, parle-nous de ton rongeur géant.
Feast on your disappointment...
Nourrissez-vous de vos regrets
...much as the capybara feasts on its own waste.
comme le capybara se nourrit de ses propres déchets.
Oh, Bella, don't you see?
Bella, tu ne comprends pas ?
Edward's only pushing you away because he loves you.
Edward te repousse parce qu'il t‘aime.
Coming.
J‘arrive.
Dr. Koothrappali?
Dr Koothrappali ?
I'm Special Agent Page, FBI. May I come in?
Je suis l‘agent spécial Page, du FBI. Puis-je entrer ?
I'd like to talk to you about Howard Wolowitz.
Je voudrais vous parler de Howard Wolowitz.
Ah, thank you.
Merci.
All right. Well, how long have you known Mr. Wolowitz?
Bien. Depuis quand connaissez-vous M. Wolowitz ?
-Rum cake? -No, thanks.
- Baba au rhum ? - Non, merci.
Now, about Mr. Wolowitz.
Et maintenant, à propos de M. Wolowitz.
Seven years.
Sept ans.
I'm in this country legally, you know.
Je suis entré légalement dans ce pays, vous savez.
I'm sure you are.
Je n'en doute pas.
Now, to your knowledge...
Selon vous,
...has Mr. Wolowitz ever committed a crime?
M. Wolowitz a-t-il déjà commis un crime ?
Of course not.
Bien sûr que non.
I'm here on an H1B visa...
J'ai un visa H1B.
...which means I can't be associated with crime or criminal activity...
Je ne peux donc être associé au crime ou à une activité criminelle
...and I'm not.
etje ne le suis pas.
To your knowledge, does Mr. Wolowitz have any foreign contacts?
Selon vous, M. Wolowitz a-t-il des contacts étrangers ?
No, just me.
Non, que moi.
Oh, there it is.
Ça y est.
Here comes the cavity search.
Je vois venir la recherche de cavité.
-Excuse me? -Please don't send me back to India.
- Pardon ? - Ne me renvoyez pas en Inde.
It's so crowded. It's like the whole country is one endless Comic-Con...
C‘est trop peuplé. Le pays est comme un interminable Comic—Con
...except everybody's wearing the same costume: Indian Guy.
sauf que tout le monde est habillé pareil : en Indien.
-Dr. Koothrappali-- -I love this country.
- Dr Koothrappali... - J'aime ce pays.
The baseball, the freedom, the rampant morbid obesity.
Le base—bali, la liberté, l‘obésité morbide rampante.
From California to the New York island, I'm a real Yankee Doodle boy.
De la Californie à l‘île de New York, je suis un vrai de vrai Yankee.
Dr. Koothrappali, please.
Dr Koothrappali, je vous en prie.
[SINGING] My country 'tis of thee
Mon pays est…
It's really great
II est formidable
So when Howard said the FBI would be contacting me...
Quand Howard m‘a dit que le FBI me contacterait,
...l was expecting Mulder.
je m‘attendais à voir Mulder.
Glad to see I got Scully, ha, ha.
Ravi d‘avoir eu Scully.
-Who? -Mulder and Scully.
-Qui ? - Mulder et Scully.
X-Files.
X-Files.
"The truth is out there." Never mind.
"La vérité est ici." Peu importe.
Uh, so, what would you like to know?
Alors, que voulez-vous savoir ?
You work with Mr. Wolowitz here at the university, correct?
Vous travaillez avec M. Wolowitz dans cette université ?
Yes. Of course, we're in different departments.
Oui. Nous ne sommes pas dans la même UFR.
He's an engineer and I'm an experimental physicist.
Il est ingénieur etje suis en physique expérimentale.
You know, one of those guys who examines...
Je fais partie de ceux qui examinent
...the building blocks of creation and says:
les composantes de la création et qui disent:
"Hello, maker of the universe.
“Ohé, créateur de l'univers.
I see what you did there.
Je vois ce que vous avez fait.
Good one."
C‘est très bien."
Right.
Oui.
Now, how would you characterize your relationship with Mr. Wolowitz?
Comment qualifieriez-vous votre relation avec M. Wolowitz ?
It's a good relationship.
C‘est une bonne relation.
Of course, most of my relationships are good, you know.
La plupart de mes relations sont bonnes, vous savez.
Probably because I exude confidence.
Parce que je transpire la confiance.
People are drawn to that, you know?
Ça attire les gens.
Confidence, not exuding.
La confiance, pas la transpiration.
Do you know of any groups Mr. Wolowitz is a member of?
Savez-vous si M. Wolowitz est membre d'un groupe ?
You are beautiful, you know that?
Vous êtes magnifique, vous savez ?
You pop, sparkle and buzz electric.
Vous êtes éclatante, rayonnante, sémillante.
I'm gonna pick you up at 8.
Je passe vous prendre à 20 h.
Show you a night you will never forget.
Ce sera une nuit inoubliable.
Sounds great.
Super.
Really?
Vraiment ?
Yeah.
Oui.
Can my 6'2" Navy SEAL husband come with us?
Mon mari de 1m90 dela Navy SEAL peut-il nous accompagner ?
Is that--? Oh, my, I didn't see the ring with my glasses off, so....
C'est... ? Bigre, je n‘avais pas vu l'alliance sans mes lunettes...
Look at that, I'm starting to exude.
Regardez, je commence à transpirer.
LEONARD: Wanna get that? -Not particularly.
- Tu veux ouvrir ? - Pas particulièrement.
-Could you get that? -I suppose I could if I were asked.
- Feux-tu ouvrir ? - Sans doute, si tu me demandes.
-Would you please get that? -Well, of course.
- Feux-tu s'il te plait ouvrir ? - Bien sûr.
Why do you have to make things so complicated?
Pourquoi tu te compliques la vie ?
-Dr. Cooper? -Yes.
- Dr Cooper ? - Oui.
I'm Special Agent Page, FBI.
Agent spécial Page, du FBI.
You say you're Special Agent Page, FBI.
Vous prétendez être l‘agent spécial Page, du FBI.
Here's my ID.
Voici ma carte.
And here is my Justice League membership card.
Et voici ma carte de membre dela Ligue des Justiciers.
But that doesn't prove I know Batman.
Ça ne prouve pas que je connaisse Batman.
I just wanna ask you a few questions about Howard Wolowitz.
Je veux vous poser quelques questions sur Howard Wolowitz.
I doubt anyone would risk the stiff penalties...
Qui risquerait une peine sévère
...for impersonating a federal officer just to ask questions...
pour se déguiser en agent fédéral pour discuter
...about a minor-league engineer with an unresolved Oedipal complex.
d'un petit ingénieur mineur souffrant d'un complexe d'Oedipe ?
-Thank you. -For the record, I truly support the FBI...
- Merci. - Sachez que je soutiens le FBI
...in the mission which is expressed through their motto.
dans sa mission exprimée par sa devise.
Fidelity, bravery, integrity?
Fidélité, bravoure, intégrité ?
Correct. Now to business.
Trés bien. Vous pouvez y aller.
Eighteen years ago, I sent the FBI Crime Lab samples...
Il y a dix-huit ans, au FBI des échantillons
...from a bag of excrement that had been lit on fire on my front porch...
d'un sac d'excréments qu'on a fait brûler devant ma porte,
...for fingerprinting and DNA analysis.
pour analyses d'empreintes et d'ADN.
Why haven't I heard back yet?
Pourquoi ne m'a-t-on toujours pas répondu ?
Well, the FBI Crime Lab does have a lot on its plate.
Le Labo du FBI a beaucoup de pain sur la planche.
That's of little comfort to a nation attempting to scrape burning feces...
Ce n‘est pas rassurant pour une nation qui veut se débarrasser
...off its shoes.
des féces sur les chaussures.
Would you mind if we talked about Mr. Wolowitz now?
Ça vous ennuierait qu'on parle de M. Wolowitz ?
A little, but go on.
Un peu, mais allez-y.
Thank you.
Merci.
Would you characterize him as responsible?
Diriez-vous qu'il est responsable ?
I'm going to answer that with a visual aid.
Je répondrai avec un support Visuel.
This is my nine-disc complete Lord of the Rings trilogy Blu-ray set.
Voici la trilogie en Blu—ray du Seigneur des Anneaux.
Mr. Wolowitz borrowed it...
M. Wolowitz l‘a emprunté,
...damaged plastic-retention hub number three...
a endommagé la retenue de plastique du numéro trois
...and then returned it to me hoping I wouldn't notice.
et me l‘a rendu, espérant que je ne remarque rien.
Would you characterize that as responsible?
Diriez-vous que c‘est responsable ?
That's really not the sort of thing we're interested in.
Ce n‘est pas le genre de chose qui nous intéresse.
-You heard me say "Blu-ray," right? -I did.
- Vous m'avez entendu dire Blu—ray ? - Oui.
Very well, would you be interested in knowing...
Trés bien. Est-ce que ça vous intéresse de savoir que
...that Mr. Wolowitz once snuck on to my "World of Warcraft" account...
M. Wolowitz s‘est introduit dans mon compte “World of Warcraft"
...and changed the name of a certain level-80 warlock...
et a changé le nom d'un warlock de niveau 80
...from "Sheldor" to "Smeldor"?
de "Sheldor" à “Smeldor" ?
I'm afraid not. Is there anything else?
J'ai bien peur que non. Il y a autre chose ?
Anything else? Where would you like to start?
Autre chose ? Par où commencer ?
He refuses to pay fines when he's overdue with books I lend him.
Il ne paye pas l'amende de retard pour les livres que je lui prête.
He crashed the Mars Rover while attempting to impress a woman.
Il a détruit le Mars Rover en voulant impressionner une femme.
He recommended that I go see the third Matrix movie...
Il m‘a recommandé d‘aller voir le troisième Matrix
...because it was, and I quote, "Just as good as the first one."
parce que, etje cite: “Il est aussi bien que le premier."
If that's not irresponsible, I don't know what is.
Si ce n‘est pas responsable, je ne sais pas ce que c'est.
The Mars Rover?
Le Mars Rover ?
-Did I say "Mars Rover"? -You did.
- J'ai dit le Mars Rover ? - Oui.
That was actually a poorly chosen example...
C‘est un exemple très mal choisi,
...as it had nothing to do with me.
et ça n‘a rien à voir avec moi.
-Yes, well, let's talk about it anyway. -I don't want to.
- Oui, eh bien, parlons—en. - Je ne veux pas.
Not that my disinclination to discuss the topic...
Non que mon manque d'enthousiasme à en parler
...should be interpreted as evidence of Howard Wolowitz's culpability...
doive signifier la culpabilité de Howard Wolowitz
...in the destruction of government property worth millions of dollars.
dans la destruction d‘une propriété de l'Etat valant des millions.
Thank you, Dr. Cooper. I think I have all I need.
Merci, Dr Cooper. J'ai tout ce qu'il me faut.
l was afraid you were going to fixate on that Mars Rover incident.
J‘avais peur que vous ne soyez obsédée par l'incident du Mars Rover.
Hey, buddies.
Salut les gars.
Guess who didn't get security clearance to work on the giant space laser.
Devinez qui n‘a pas eu son certificat pour bosser sur le laser géant ?
-What happened? -Background interviews didn't go well.
- Que s'est-il passé ? - L‘enquête s‘est mal passée.
You guys wouldn't know anything about that, would you?
Évidemment, vous n‘êtes au courant de rien.
Well, actually, I may have gotten a little tipsy when I talked to her.
En fait, j‘étais peut-ètre pompette quand je lui ai parlé.
And I may have hit on her a little bit.
Je l'ai peut-être un peu trop draguée.
And I may have thrown up rum cake on her shoes.
J'ai peut-être fait tomber du gâteau sur ses chaussures.
I see. Well, it's good to know when I need you guys...
Je vois. C‘est bon de savoir que quand j'ai besoin de vous,
...I can always count on you to step up and ruin everything.
je peux toujours compter sur vous pout tout gâcher.
-| feel awful. -Me too.
- Je me sens mal. - Moi aussi.
I thought if anyone was gonna screw things up for Howard...
Je croyais que si quelqu'un devait gâcher le truc,
...it'd be Sheldon.
ça aurait été Sheldon.
Well, your expectations have been subverted.
Eh bien, tes attentes auront été déçues.
What are you doing up?
Qu'est- ce que tu fais debout ?
Sleep eludes me, Leonard.
Le sommeil me fuit, Leonard.
Really?
Vraiment ?
Maybe sleep has met you before.
Le sommeil te connait peut- étre.
Mockery? That's all you have to offer?
La moquerie ? C‘est tout ce que tu as à offrir ?
-Sorry. Why can't you sleep? -Who knows?
- Pardon. Pourquoi tu ne dors pas ? - Qui sait ?
I haven't watched any scary movies recently.
Je n'ai pas vu de film d‘horreur récemment.
I'm no longer obsessing over why the predicted mass...
Je ne me demande plus pourquoi la masse prévisible
...of the quantum vacuum has little effect on the expansion of the universe.
du vide quantique a peu d‘effet sur l‘expansion de l'univers.
And it's been weeks since I took that accidental sip of Red Bull.
Et ça fait des semaines que j'ai bu par erreur une gorgée de Red Bull.
Something happen today that's bothering you?
S'est- il passé quelque chose qui t‘a dérangé ?
Well, I did mention the Mars Rover incident to that FBI agent...
J'ai parlé de l'incident du Mars Rover à l‘agent du FBI
...and probably cost Howard his security clearance.
ce qui a pu nuire au certificat de sécurité de Howard.
-What? -Yeah, but why should that keep me up?
- Quoi ? - Pourquoi ça m‘empêche de dormir ?
Because you feel guilty?
Parce que tu te sens coupable ?
Interesting.
Intéressant.
So you're saying my insomnia is caused by a guilty conscience?
Mon insomnie serait provoquée par un sentiment de culpabilité.
Actually, you don't have insomnia. You're sleeping now.
En fait, tu n'as pas d‘insomnie. Tu dors, en ce moment.
-Excuse me? -You're having a guilt-ridden dream.
- Pardon ? - C‘est un rêve de culpabilité.
Do you have any evidence to support that hypothesis?
Tu as une preuve au soutien de cette hypothèse ?
How about that Gorn sitting on the couch?
Le Gorn assis sur le canapé ?
That seems fairly conclusive.
C‘est assez concluant.
No, Gorn, no.
Non, Gorn, non.
That's where I sit.
C‘est ma place.
Thank you for agreeing to see me, Agent Page.
Merci d‘avoir accepté de me voir, agent Page.
Thank you for filing a complaint with my superior, Dr. Cooper.
Merci d‘avoir porté plainte auprès de mon supérieur, Dr Cooper.
I understand you wanna recant your statement about Howard Wolowitz?
Vous voulez vous rétracter au sujet de Howard Wolowitz.
-Yes. -Was your statement untrue?
- Oui. - Votre déposition était fausse ?
Then I'm afraid you can't withdraw it.
Dans ce cas, vous ne pouvez vous rétracter.
I'm sorry, I don't recall you saying no backsies.
Pardon, vous n'avez jamais dit: "Pas touche".
Is there anything else?
Il y a autre chose ?
Yes, I'd like to offer a laudatory statement...
Oui, j'aimerais vous proposer quelques éloges
...about Howard's many excellent qualities I believe will tip the scales...
sur les qualités de Howard qui pourraient faire pencher la balance
...back in his favor. Ahem. "Howard Joel Wolowitz.
en sa faveur. "Howard Joel Wolowitz.
H is for 'honesty,' of which he has much.
H pour l‘honnêteté dont il ne manque pas.
O is for 'outstanding,' which he is such.
O pour original, qui est sa marque.
W is for 'witty.' He's quick with a joke.
W pour wagnérien comme dans grandiose.
A is for 'artistic,' his ability--"
A pour artistique, car son talent..."
I'm sorry, Dr. Cooper, this matter is already closed.
Désolé, Dr Cooper, mais le dossier est clos.
But I still have "ard Joel Wolowitz" left to go.
Il reste encore "ard Joel Wolowitz".
It's closed.
Le sujet est clos.
I don't understand why you people are picking on my friend Howard...
Je ne comprends pas pourquoi vous embêtez Howard
...when there are much more serious security threats to pursue.
alors qu'il y a des menaces encore plus sérieuses.
For instance, when I first met Leonard...
Par exemple, quand j'ai connu Leonard,
...he was on the verge of giving away rocket secrets to a North Korean spy...
il était sur le point de filer des secrets à un espion nord-coréen
...and not one agent ever investigated that.
et pas un seul agent n‘ajamais enquêté.
This is Leonard Hofstadter?
Vous parlez de Leonard Hofstadter ?
No, it's a different Leonard. He's Chinese, red hair, six fingers.
Non, un autre Leonard. C‘est un Chinois roux à six doigts.
Goodbye.
Au revoir.
Raj, have you seen Howard?
Raj, tu as vu Howard ?
I think he's eating lunch.
Il est à la cafétéria.
Uh, Sheldon, I want you to meet Neil DeGrasse Tyson...
Sheldon, voici Neil DeGrasse Tyson
...from the Hayden Planetarium in New York.
du planétarium Hayden de New York.
He's responsible for the demotion of Pluto from planetary status.
C‘est à cause de lui que Pluton a perdu son statut de planète.
I liked Pluto...
J'aimais Pluton,
-...ergo, I do not like you. -But I actually didn't demote Pluto.
- donc, je ne vous aime pas. - Ce n‘est pas moi.
That was a vote of the International Astronomical Union.
C‘est un vote de l‘Union Astronomique Internationale.
If ifs and buts were candy and nuts, we'd all have a merry Christmas.
Si les si et les mais étaient des entremets, ce serait Noël.
Think about that, Dr. Tyson.
Pensez-y, Dr Tyson.
That the guy you were telling me about?
C‘est le garçon dont vous me parliez ?
Oh, yeah.
Oui.
Howard, the person at fault for you not getting a security clearance is me.
Howard, le responsable de ton échec pour la sécurité, c‘est moi.
-You? -Yes, but before you get upset...
- Toi ? - Oui, mais avant de te fâcher,
...I want you to know I went to the FBI and retracted my statement.
sache que je suis allé me rétracter au FBI.
And they were okay with that?
Alors tout va bien ?
No. If anything, I made it worse.
Non. En fait, ça a empiré les choses.
In any case, I have been riddled with guilt...
De toute façon, je suis rongé parla culpabilité
...which is causing Gorn-infested REM sleep.
ce qui me fait un sommeil hanté par les Gorns.
-So I'm here now to say I'm sorry. -Are you kidding me?
- Alors je te présente mes excuses. - Tu plaisantes ?
You've set my career back at least two years...
Tu as ralentis ma carrière d'au moins deux ans
...and you think you can make it right with "I'm sorry"?
et tu crois que tu peux t'en tirer avec des excuses ?
Yes.
Oui.
I followed the social protocol.
J'ai suivi le protocole.
I attempted to right the wrong and when I failed...
J'ai voulu réparer mes torts et aprés avoir échoué,
...I delivered a heartfelt apology. Now, you say, "Apology accepted"...
je te présente mes excuses. Tu dois dire : "Je les accepte"
...and I will offer you a one-time-only high five.
etje t‘offrirai, mais qu‘une fois, mon tope.
Your apology is not accepted.
Je n‘accepte pas tes excuses.
You're tricking me. It really is, isn't it?
Tu rigoles. N'est-ce pas ?
Leave me alone, Sheldon.
Laisse—moi tranquille, Sheldon.
Dr. Cooper, | just wanted you to know...
Dr Cooper, je voulais vous dire que
...l'm sorry for the role I played in the Pluto matter.
je suis désolé pour le rôle que j'ai pu jouer dans l‘affaire Pluton.
Oh, shut up.
Taisez-vous.
-Sheldon? -Hello.
- Sheldon ? - Salut.
What are you doing here?
Qu'est-ce que tu fais la ?
l have troubles, Penny.
J'ai des ennuis, Penny.
I've come to pour them out to the sympathetic ear of the local barkeep.
Je Viens les déverser à l‘oreille sympathique dela barmaid du coin.
You know, they have a really nice bar over at the Olive Garden.
Tu sais, il y a un très joli bar au Olive Garden.
I don't like the Olive Garden. They treat me like family.
Je n'aime pas le Olive Garden. On me traite avec familiarité.
-Okay, Sheldon, what can I get you? -Alcohol.
- Alors, qu'est-ce que je te sers ? - De l‘alcool.
-Could you be a little more specific? -Ethyl alcohol.
- Tu peux être plus précis ? - De l'alcool éthylique.
Forty milliliters.
Quarante millimètres.
I'm sorry, honey, I don't know milliliters.
Désolé, chéri, je ne connais pas les millimètres.
Ah. Blame President James Jimmy Carter.
La faute au président James Jimmy Carter.
He started America on a path to the metric system but then just gave up.
Il nous a lancés sur le chemin du système métrique
He wonders why he was a one-term president.
On se demande pourquoi il n‘a été élu qu‘une fois.
-Would you say that's 40 milliliters? -More or less.
- Tu crois que c‘est 40 millimètres ? - Plus ou moins.
Great.
Super.
Now, where were we?
Où en étions-nous ?
I believe you were about to ask me to choose a cocktail.
Tu m'as demandé de choisir un cocktail.
Fortunately, thanks to computer-savvy alcoholics...
Par chance, grâce aux alcooliques fous d'informatiques,
...there's an app for that.
il y a une application pour ça.
Let's see. "Harvey Wallbanger." Eh.
Voyons. Harvey Wallbanger.
"Sex on the Beach." I hardly think so.
Sex on the Beach. Je ne pense pas.
"Rob Roy, Silk Slipper, Mad Hatter."
Rob Roy, Soulier de satin, Mad Hatter.
-l'll have a Rosewater Rickey. -A what?
- Ce sera un Rosewater Rickey. - Un quoi ?
"You'll need pitted, brandied cherries, gin...
"Cerises dénoyautés dans Ie brandy, gin,
...rosewater, Angostura bitters and over-proofed rum.
eau de rose, bitter additionné d‘angustura et rhum.
Now, first, dust the cherries with sugar...
Saupoudrez d‘abord du sucre sur les cerises,
...then spray them with a mixture of rum and bitters.
puis aspergez-les d'un mélange de rhum et de bitter.
-Then ignite the rum--" -Here you go, one Rosewater Rickey.
- Faites flamber le rhum..." - Tiens, ton Rosewater Rickey.
That's not how it looks in the picture.
Ça ne lui ressemble pas.
Oh, yeah, every bartender makes it differently.
Oui, à chaque barmaid sa recette.
-Why don't you give it a try? -All right.
- Essaie pour voir. - D‘accord.
To the metric system.
Au système métrique.
I can't taste the cherries.
Ça n‘a pas le goût de cerise.
All right, Sheldon, what's on your mind?
Alors, qu'est-ce qui te tracasse ?
l wronged Howard and he won't accept my apology.
J'ai trahi Howard et il n‘accepte pas mes excuses.
Oh, right, that.
Ah, oui, ça.
Yes, Leonard told me. Sorry, honey.
Leonard m'en a parlé. Désolé, chéri.
Penny, you face failure on a daily basis.
Penny, tu affrontes l‘échec au quotidien.
-How do you cope? -| drink.
- Comment fais-tu ? - Je bois.
To drinking.
Ala beuverie.
If only there were some way to force Howard to accept my apology...
Si seulementje pouvais forcer Howard d'accepter mes excuses
...so I could escape this miasma of guilt.
pour que je m‘arrache aux miasmes dela culpabilité.
Sometimes stuffjust happens and there's nothing you can do about it.
Les choses arrivent parfois et on n‘y peut rien.
For example, Lisa Peterson hasn't talked to me since 11th grade.
Prends Lisa Peterson qui ne m‘a pas parlé depuis la seconde.
No matter how much you apologize...
On a beau s'excuser,
...you can't go back and un-dry-hump someone's boyfriend.
on ne se défrotte pas du petit ami de quelqu‘un.
You're saying I'm facing Starfleet Academy's...
Je suis dans le scénario de l'Académie de Starfleet
...unwinnable command scenario: the Kobayashi Maru.
dela commande impossible: Le Kobayashi Maru.
Exactly. Sometimes you can't win.
Exactement. Il arrive qu'on ne puisse pas gagner.
Captain Kirk won.
Le capitaine Kirk a gagné.
Kirk cheated.
Kirk a triché.
Impressive that you know that.
C‘est impressionnant que tu saches ça.
Hard to believe I'm actually having this conversation with you.
J'ai du mal à croire que j'ai cette conversation avec toi.
Right there with you.
Tout à fait d‘accord.
Kirk beat the Kobayashi Maru by reprogramming the simulator.
Kirk a gagné le Kobayashi Maru en reprogrammant le simulateur.
-That's it. -What?
- Mais oui. - Quoi ?
I'll reprogram Howard.
Je vais reprogrammer Howard.
Wait-- Sheldon, you can't reprogram people.
Attends... Tu ne peux pas reprogrammer des gens.
No, you can't reprogram people.
Non. Tu ne peux pas
To James Tiberius Kirk.
A James Tiberius Kirk.
-Hello, all. LEONARD: Hello.
- Salut, tout le monde. - Salut.
Howard, you're feeling better about me today, aren't you?
Howard, tu es mieux disposé à mon endroit aujourd'hui, hein ?
-Not really. -Yes, you are.
- Pas vraiment. - Mais si.
I'm using neuro-linguistic programming to modify your thought patterns.
J'ai recours àla programmation neurolinguistique pour t‘influencer.
Go away, Sheldon.
Va-t'en, Sheldon.
There's a 9.95 eBook down the drain.
Adieu eBook à 9,95.
-What's in the bag? -lt's for Howard.
- C‘est quoi dans le sac ? - C‘est pour Howard.
No, Sheldon, you can't fix this with gifts.
Non, ça ne s‘arrange pas avec des cadeaux.
Nevertheless, I've hurt you and whether you forgive me or not...
Néanmoins, je t'ai blessé et que tu me pardonnes ou pas,
...I want you to have this.
je veux te donner ça.
You're giving me a couch cushion?
Tu me donnes un coussin de canapé ?
No. The cushion is merely symbolic.
Non. Le coussin est symbolique.
I'm giving you my spot on the couch.
Je te donne ma place sur le canapé.
But you love that spot.
Mais tu aimes cette place.
No, I love my mother.
Non, j'aime ma mère.
My feelings for my spot are much greater.
Mes sentiments pour cette place son beaucoup plus forts.
It's the singular location in space around which revolves my entire universe.
C‘est le seul endroit autour duquel tourne tout mon univers.
And now it's yours.
Et maintenant il est à toi.
Oh, my God, dude, now you have to forgive him.
Ça alors, mec, il faut que tu lui pardonnes.
All right. Uh, apology accepted.
D‘accord. J‘accepte tes excuses.
High five.
Tope.
Not too hard.
Pas trop fort.
Thank you.
Merci.
I haven't cried like this since Toy Story 3.
Je n'ai pas pleuré comme ça depuis Toy Story 3.
I gotta tell you, Sheldon, I understand why you chose this spot.
J‘avoue que je comprends pourquoi tu choisis cette place.
I mean, the temperature's good, but there's no draft.
La température est agréable, il n‘y a pas de courant d'air.
I can see the television, but I can still talk to--
Je peux regarder la télé tout en parlant à...
I changed my mind. Get out of my spot.
J'ai changé d‘idée. Rends-moi ma place.
-How long? -Ninety-four seconds.
- Combien de temps ? - Quatre-vingt-quatorze secondes.
[English - us - an]
[French]